$\mathsf{C} \ \mathsf{O} \ \mathsf{N} \ \mathsf{T} \ \mathsf{A} \ \mathsf{C} \ \mathsf{T}$

CELL +27 (0) 73 579 4587

EMAIL

matthewh.holmes@yahoo.com

RIGHT TO WORK EU & South Africa

LINKEDIN

Profile

Github

Profile This CV

CAREER

ENTERPRISE

PRODUCT

FREELANCE

SPECIALIST

C# 9

.NET 5 Web API

React

ChilliCream GraphQL

Javascript

Typescript

SASS

Material UI

Azure DevOps

SQL

Azure

Selenium

M A T T H E W H O L M E S

PROFILE

I am a full-stack senior software engineer with a cumulative total of 6 years of experience. I have experience in large, complex enterprise domains as a salaried full-time developer. I also have experience contracting and freelancing independently. In particular, most of my expertise is in .NET applications with React front-ends. However, I have picked up other technologies such as Anglular and WPF with ease in order to deliver on smaller projects.

I have worked on data and integration heavy Service Oriented Architectures, as well as websites with beautiful front-ends designed by UX Design Specialists. I can readily work for EU companies because I am an Italian citizen, and South African companies where I am both a citizen and resident.

EXPERIENCE

ENTELECT

Senior Software Engineer / Nov 2020 - Present

I returned to Entelect as a full-time Senior Engineer, based on an Anglo American project. I have worked on building major parts of a Service Oriented Architecture in Azure. This included the development using Azure Functions, App Services, Service Bus, Azure SQL and Azure IaC. Additionally, the user-facing portions of the application were built using a vertical slice code layout with a CQRS pattern. The front-end was built in React and Material UI and needed to make use of Anglo's design system. I additionally designed and implemented a GraphQL endpoint for fetching organisational data by multiple applications. Due to application security requried in the SOA, I implemented several Azure authentication flows such as MSAL, On-Behalf Flow and Client Credentials Flow.

I supported the Technical Lead by making the smaller architectural decisions, and was responsible for providing oversight and mentorship to the other more junior developers on the team.

INDEPENDENT FREELANCER

Aug 2020 - October 2020

Built a proof of concept for a Fintech application leveraging the Plaid API.

ACQUAINTED

Angular

WPF

Bootstrap 5

Azure IaC

SSRS

EDUCATION

BSc(Hons) Computer Science (Cum Laude)

University of the Witwatersrand 2013

BSc Computer Science & Applied Mathematics
University of the Witwatersrand
2012

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft

MCSD App Builder 2019

PRESENTATIONS

SQL Server Performance Tuning Fundamentals

Introduction to Web Assembly and Blazor

MATTHEW HOLMES

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

BUSINESS SCIENCE CORPORATION

Senior Developer / Sept 2019 - Jul 2020 Intermediate Developer / Sept 2018 - Aug 2019

Responsible for leading the South African contingent of the development team, reporting to the Delivery Manager. This included mentoring juniors and intermediates, conducting interviews, and driving technical change. I also Career Managed two junior developers.

The project involved a large migration from angular.js (V1) to React while delivering features and maintenance in parallel. I implemented measures to improve maintainability and efficiency. This included the migration of weakly typed Typescript to stronger typing rules and analysing and introducing strict linting rules to reduce bug counts coming back from QA. I played a major role in driving this 11-man team to start adopting some SCRUM processes to improve planning and efficiency. Introducing this lead to clearer client excpectations and happier developers.

ACTOM

Independent Contractor / Jan 2017 - Jan 2018

Sub-contracted to migrate a 30 000+ line of code HT-BASIC application built in the 1970s to a modern desktop application. I rewrote the application in C# WPF. The application assisted engineers to design electric motors. Since this was a client I landed in my personal capacity, I performed requirements analysis, pipeline planning, prioritisation, development and testing. This was done on the side, after working hours. My main employer (Entelect, below) was aware that I had this project and was okay with this as my performance was solid.

ENTELECT

Senior Software Engineer / Jan 2017 - May 2018 Software Engineer / Oct 2014 - Dec 2016

Based on a Deloitte Customs and Excise ASP.NET MVC project. Responsible for requirements elicitation, SDLC management, business and technical analysis, mentorship, development pipeline planning and prioritisation, deadline negotiation, technical investigations and research. Project managed and lead a major upgrade from SQL 2008 to SQL 2016, Entity Framework 4 to Entity Framework 6, Bootstrap 2 to Bootstrap 3, and major in-house library upgrades. Lead the technical investigation, decision making and migration to use Microsoft Azure Active Directory for Identity Management.